#### Contact

shobhitsinha13@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/shobhit-anupriya-sinha (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Data Analysis
Project Management
Research

## Languages

Hindi (Elementary) English (Elementary) Sanskrit (Elementary)

#### Certifications

Intermediate Importing Data in Python

Cleaning Data in Python

Six Sigma: Green Belt

Introduction to Data Visualization with Matplotlib

Python Data Science Toolbox (Part 1)

#### Honors-Awards

Indian Delegate: CYL Youth Entrepreneurship

# Shobhit Anupriya Sinha

 Research Intern @IIITD • Lead @GirlScript Patiala • Core @DSC TIET • Exploring Quant Research • Former Intern @OpenGenus • Junior Year, Thapar University

Delhi

# Summary

This is Shobhit Sinha, a junior year undergraduate student pursuing my bachelor's in Engineering from Thapar University, Patiala. My background is filled with exploration in the field of Marketing, Content & strategy in past to Research, Coding, Projects, Data Analysis & Development at present. With a creative attitude of problemsolving to maximize opportunities by connecting every customer with personal support is my aim.

Right from the start I was very curious and wanted to try & experiment a different set of fields that I came across. I wanted to challenge myself as much as I can. I completed two internships as a Content Writer Intern and Social Media Marketing Intern at Jeet and Thrillzone NGO respectively by the end of the first year.

In the second year, the journey in the technical field started. Fortunately, I managed to accomplish various things: Creating an app on Assistant, HacktoberFest etc. organizing tech talks, competitions and Hackathon and delivering a talk on Edge computing,

Soon after 3rd semester, I got an opportunity to intern as Research Scientist at OpenGenus Foundation. And as soon as I was done with my internship, I got an amazing offer to Intern at Indraprastha Institute of Information & Technology, Delhi under CSED-Head Dr Vikram Goyal and Shad Akhtar in spatial temporal Data Analytics.

I'm currently heading two separate communities GirlScript Patiala (Lead) and TEDxTIET(Head of Technical and staging).

During these years of my college, I have done 10+ courses and gained a lot of knowledge across various domain that I would love to incorporate dealing with the current scenario.

Moreover, I've completed 7+ projects (1 internship project, 3 main and some small projects) in the field of Data Analysis, Web Development and Messaging based.

You can check my Github profile for the same: https://github.com/Shobhs13

Apart from that,

- I recently volunteered with UNV INDIA for the COVID-19 campaign.
- I am a writer at Quora who have over 500K+ views writing all about JEE, JEET Academy, success, failure, habit & ideas for a good living.

https://www.quora.com/profile/Shobhit-Sinha-18

I won't call my self a Kaggle as of now as I'm new to it, But, if you want to have a look at it.

https://www.kaggle.com/shobhitsinha

I'll be soon starting to write more on Medium as well. https://medium.com/@shobhitsinha13

That was all for my bio!

I'm still learning the logic behind various data fields as well and also open to all opportunities in the field on Data Analyst, Research Analyst and Project Management.

# Experience

Indraprastha Institute of Information Technology, Delhi 4 months

Undergraduate Student Researcher July 2020 - Present (2 months)

Summer Research Intern May 2020 - July 2020 (3 months) Delhi, India

- Worked under the supervision of Dr Vikram Goyal on Spatial-Temporal Data Analytics.
- Scraped, cleaned, and tokenized 8000 tweets for our model.

• Build a machine learning model to predicted congestion on roads of Delhi by analyzing crowdsource information and plotting it on the map.

GirlScript Chapter Patiala

1 year 2 months

Chapter Lead
April 2020 - Present (5 months)

Patiala, Punjab

Core Organizer July 2019 - April 2020 (10 months)

#### **TEDxTIET**

1 year 6 months

Head of Technical and Staging Department December 2019 - Present (9 months)

Executive Team Member March 2019 - December 2019 (10 months) Patiala Area, India

Developer Student Club Thapar Technical Core Member August 2020 - Present (1 month)

Patiala, Punjab, India

Skillenza
Campus Hustler
April 2020 - Present (5 months)

OpenGenus Foundation Research Scientist Intern December 2019 - May 2020 (6 months)

- Led 7 article projects based articles that focused on different computer concepts across the various domain.
- Worked on Open-source based GNU debugger and memory leakage.
- Managed the OpenGenus IQ platform and worked on different tasks.

UnsaidTalks
Content Editor
September 2018 - May 2020 (1 year 9 months)

#### Patiala, Punjab, India

- A startup by the ex. Thapar University alumni which deals with detailed procedure of selection in placements.
- Team member and Editor of UnsaidTalks.
- Placement talks, event and to get placement assistance.

link:- https://www.unsaidtalks.com/

#### Thrill Zone

Social Media Marketing Intern January 2019 - February 2019 (2 months)

Thrill Zone aims at promoting healthy living across the country.

Used SEO to enhance the content.

Optimization tools to reach the crowd effectively and efficiently.

Targeted social media platforms (Instagram, Facebook and popular websites). Identifying the demand for keywords.

#### **JEET**

Content Writer and Marketing Intern November 2018 - January 2019 (3 months) Patiala, Punjab, India

- Writing blog for a coaching institute 'JEET' for JEE related procedure and queries. The coaching institure is based out in Kanpur, U.P, India and run by director Sudhanshu Mishra (ex alumni IIT-BHU).

# Education

## **Thapar University**

Bachelor of Engineering - BE, Electronics and Computer Engineering · (2018 - 2022)

#### Kulachi Hansraj Model School

Senior secondary, Non-Medical with Engineering Drawing · (2008 - 2018)